<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Economics on Swopnil Shrestha | Software Engineer</title>
    <link>//swopnil.com/tags/economics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Economics on Swopnil Shrestha | Software Engineer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Swopnil Shrestha {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 02:08:54 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//swopnil.com/tags/economics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Disability Underemployment in the United States: A Product of Structural Impairments</title>
      <link>//swopnil.com/blog/disability-unemployment-us-ada/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 02:08:54 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//swopnil.com/blog/disability-unemployment-us-ada/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Issues of employment are of the utmost importance to disabled individuals in the United States as it determines the quality of life they will have. Whether a disabled individual is able to support a family and pursue their own dreams or lives a meager life in poverty often correlates with their place on the economic ladder. How will the disabled individual provide for their family? How will they afford to buy a house or purchase goods that they require for self-sustenance?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The United States and China in the AI Economy</title>
      <link>//swopnil.com/blog/us-china-ai-relations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 12:27:37 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//swopnil.com/blog/us-china-ai-relations/</guid>
      <description>人工智能经济中的中国和美国
Current State of AI in the World (世界AI的现状) Artificial Intelligence (AI) was founded on the premise that computational intelligence could match or surpass the intelligence of a human. Also called 人工智能 in simplified Chinese, this term describes machines that are capable doing complex and high-level jobs that only humans are currently capable of doing, having cognitive functions with the human mind like learning and function. Since its conception in 1956 as an academic discipline, AI has already been able to impact our lives in a massive way, revolutionizing many aspects of industry with tasks such as text, speech and image recognition, autonomous driving, content delivery networks music and art.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
